export const QuizData = [
  {
    question: "When was Dr. Ambedkar born?",
    a: "14th April, 1891",
    b: "14th April, 1893",
    c: "11th April, 1890",
    d: "14th March, 1892",
    correct: "14th April, 1891"
  },
  {
    question: "What was the name of Dr. Ambedkar's father?",
    a: "Ramji Maloji Sakpal",
    b: "Sambha ji Sakpal",
    c: "Yashwant Sambha Ambedkar",
    d: "None of these",
    correct: "Ramji Maloji Sakpal"
  },
  {
    question: "When was Dr. Ambedkar given Bharat Ratna?",
    a: "1980",
    b: "1990",
    c: "1985",
    d: "1979",
    correct: "1990"
  },
  {
    question: "What is the name of Dr. Ambedkar's memorial site?",
    a: "Samta sthal",
    b: "Chaityabhoomi",
    c: "Buddhist bhumi",
    d: "Deekshabhoomi",
    correct: "Chaityabhoomi"
  },
  {
    question:
      "Dr. Ambedkar was the chairman of which committee constituted to form the Indian Constitution?",
    a: "Preamble committee",
    b: "Drafting committee",
    c: "Flag committee",
    d: "Union constiitution committee",
    correct: "Drafting committee"
  },
  {
    question:
      "Which of the following books has not been written by Dr. Ambedkar?",
    a: "Thoughts on Pakistan",
    b: "Annihilation of caste",
    c: "The problem of Rupee",
    d: "Gandhi, Nehru and Tagore",
    correct: "Gandhi, Nehru and Tagore"
  },
  {
    question:
      "Which of the following magazine was not launched by Dr. Ambedkar?",
    a: "Mooknayak",
    b: "Bahishkrit Bharat",
    c: "Prabuddh Bharat",
    d: "Saraswati",
    correct: "Saraswati"
  },
  {
    question:
      "Which of the following political parties has not been formed by Dr. Ambedkar?",
    a: "Republican Party Of India",
    b: "Indian Labour Party",
    c: "Scheduled Caste Federation",
    d: "Socialist party of India",
    correct: "Socialist party of India"
  },
  {
    question:
      "In which year did Dr Ambedkar embrace Buddhism along with his lakhs of followers?",
    a: "1949",
    b: "1951",
    c: "1956",
    d: "1948",
    correct: "1956"
  },
  {
    question: "Which book is considered as the Magmum Opus of Dr Ambedkar?",
    a: "The Buddha And His Dhamma",
    b: "Revolution And Counter-Revolution",
    c: "Riddles in Hinduism",
    d: "State And Minorities",
    correct: "The Buddha And His Dhamma"
  },
  {
    question:
      "Where was the 4th World Buddhist Conference held where Babasaheb delivered his infamous speech 'Buddha Or Karl Marx'?",
    a: "Ceylon",
    b: "Burma",
    c: "Nepal",
    d: "Japan",
    correct: "Nepal"
  },
  {
    question: "Who were Babasaheb's 3 gurus?",
    a: "Ranade, Gandhi & Jinnah",
    b: "Buddha, Kabir & Jotiba Phule",
    c: "Shivaji maharaj, Sant Tukaram, Chokhamela",
    d: "Jesus,  King Ashoka & Guru Nanak",
    correct: "Buddha, Kabir & Jotiba Phule"
  },
  {
    question:
      "When was the historic speech 'What way Emancipation?' speech delivered by Dr Ambedkar?",
    a: "31st May, 1936",
    b: "13th October, 1935",
    c: "14th April, 1939",
    d: "6th June, 1934",
    correct: "31st May, 1936"
  },
  {
    question: "Between whom was the Poona Pact signed?",
    a: "Dr Ambedkar and Nehru",
    b: "Dr Ambedkar and Gandhi",
    c: "Dr Ambedkar and Sardar patel",
    d: "Dr Ambedkar and Rajendra Prasad",
    correct: "Dr Ambedkar and Gandhi"
  },
  {
    question:
      "According to Dr. Ambedkar which Article is the most important article of Indian constitution?",
    a: "Article 21",
    b: "Article 24",
    c: "Article 32",
    d: "Article 49",
    correct: "Article 32"
  },
  {
    question: "How many Doctoral degrees did Ambedkar have?",
    a: "1",
    b: "2",
    c: "3",
    d: "4",
    correct: "4"
  },
  {
    question: "Which form of government Dr Ambedkar preferred?",
    a: "Constitutional Democracry",
    b: "Monarchy",
    c: "Artistocracy",
    d: "None of the above",
    correct: "Constitutional Democracry"
  },
  {
    question: "In which college did Dr Ambedkar study in India?",
    a: "Hindu College",
    b: "Elphinstone College",
    c: "Delhi College",
    d: "Isabella College",
    correct: "Elphinstone College"
  },
  {
    question: "What portfolio was handled by Dr Ambedkar in Independent India",
    a: "Home Ministry",
    b: "Finance Ministry",
    c: "Education Ministry",
    d: "Law Ministry",
    correct: "Law Ministry"
  },
  {
    question:
      " Who provided scholarship to Dr. Ambedkar for his studies abroad?",
    a: "Maharaja of Kolhapu",
    b: "Nizam of Hyderabad",
    c: "Travancore of Maharaja",
    d: "Maharaja of Baroda",
    correct: "Maharaja of Baroda"
  },
  {
    question: "From whom did Dr Ambedkar derive his philosophy of life?",
    a: "Karl Marx",
    b: "Lord Buddha",
    c: "John Dewey",
    d: "Jotiba Phule",
    correct: "Lord Buddha"
  },

  {
    question:
      "At which place Babasaheb embraced Buddhism with his lakhs of followers?",
    a: "Mumbai",
    b: "Nagpur",
    c: "Delhi",
    d: "Baroda",
    correct: "Nagpur"
  }
];
